Ann Bridge:
Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center,
Ann Bridge [pseudonym of Mary Dolling Sanders O'Malley] Papers
1815-1973
bulk 1905-1973
The University of Texas at Austin, Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center
Bridge, Ann, 1889-1974
30 Boxes (12.6 linear feet), 1 Oversize Folder
This collection contains Bridge's manuscripts of books, other writings, and unpublished works as well as correspondence, scrapbooks of clippings and letters, and photographs.
TXRC95-A3
Index Terms
People
Adrian, Edgar Douglas Adrian, Baron, 1889-1977.; Amery, L. S. (Leopold Stennett), 1873-1955.; Baring, Maurice, 1874-1945.; Barnes, Ronald Gorell Barnes, Baron, 1884-1963.; Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, 1879-1964.; Betjeman, John, Sir, 1906- .; Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943.; Bland, Nevile, Sir, b. 1886.; Bottomley, Gordon, 1874-1948.; Cunninghame Graham, Angus, Sir, 1893-1981.; Derwent, George Harcourt Johnston, Baron, 1899-1949.; Ernst, Morris L. (Morris Leopold), 1888- .; Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan), 1879-1970.; Furse, Ralph Dolignon, Sir, 1887- .; Gaselee, S. (Stephen), 1882-1943.; Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1878-1957.; Lang, Cosmo Gordon Lang, baron, Abp. of Canterbury, 1864-1945.; Lindsay, Loelia Mary Grosvenor, Duchess of, 1902- .; Mackworth, Margaret Haig Thomas, Viscountess Rhondda, b. 1883.; Marsh, Edward Howard, Sir, 1872-1953.; Masefield, Charles J. B. (Charles John Beech), 1882-1917.; Masefield, John, 1878-1967.; McIntyre, Alfred R.; Mendl, Charles, Sir, 1871-1958.; Mitchison, Naomi, 1897- .; O'Malley, Owen St. Clair, Sir, 1887- .; Peters, A. D.; Queneau, Raymond, 1903-1976.; Richards, I. A. (Ivor Armstrong), 1893- .; Roberts, Denys Kilham, 1903-1976.; Robertson, David.; Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962.; Schumann, Elisabeth.; Strang, William Strang, Baron, 1893- .; Weeks, Edward, 1898- .; West, Rebecca, Dame, 1892- .; Wilson, Steuart.
Subjects
Albania--Description and travel--1936.; Authors, English.; China--Description and travel--1925-1927.; Dalmatia (Croatia)--Description and travel--1930.; Day family.; Portugal--Description and travel--1946-1947.; Saunders family.; Women authors, English.; Brooking family.
Document Types
First drafts.; Juvenilia.; Photograph albums.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sheet music.; Tintypes.
Scope and Contents
The papers of British author Lady Mary Dolling Sanders O'Malley, who wrote under the pseudonym Ann Bridge, consist largely of her holograph manuscripts for books published from 1932 through 1973. Also included are manuscripts of poems, short stories, articles, reviews, and lectures, as well as manuscripts of unpublished works. Correspondence, scrapbooks of clippings and letters, and a few photographs are also present.
Lady O'Malley compiled an extensive inventory of her papers which identifies and describes this collection in great detail. Her original list contains much description, identification, and commentary not available in the collection itself, and forms a valuable manuscript in and of itself. The list often includes synopses or transcriptions of correspondence in the collection. The papers have been unpacked and rehoused in archival folders and boxes, and arranged to respect her original order and to facilitate use of the many internal cross references within her inventory.
Her original order divides manuscripts for published book-length works (arranged chronologically, 1932-1969) from the rest of the papers, which are subdivided into Appendices A-R. These appendices contain other genres of manuscripts, research material, correspondence, etc., which are also usually arranged chronologically. The following folder list, which identifies the particular boxes and folders in which the collection is now housed, should be used in conjunction with the O'Malley inventory attached. Additional materials not described in Lady O'Malley's original inventory were found and are noted at the end of this list.
Though the papers chiefly concern Lady O'Malley's works and their publication, there is correspondence relating to her experiences as the wife of a diplomat, some of which were incorporated into her writings. These include her impressions while traveling in China (1925-27), Dalmatia (1930), Albania (1936), and Portugal (1946-47). Also of interest are a small group of letters written by others to Lady O'Malley which describe wartime England, 1940-41. Her relief work in Hungary (1940-41), Poland (1944-45), and France (post World War II) is also documented. Four very large files of correspondence, chiefly 1953-1954, represent her research for Portrait of My Mother, and contain extensive genealogical information concerning the Brooking, Day, and Sanders families. Among this research material are originals and transcripts of early family letters, 1815-1898, by William Day, Hannah Hinman, Marie Louise Day Sanders, John Baldwin, James Ingersoll Day, and Mrs. James I. Day. Correspondence with David Robertson, George Mallory's son-in-law, concerns O'Malley's unpublished manuscript and research materials on Mallory.
In addition to O'Malley's outgoing correspondence (present in both originals and carbons) are numerous letters from family, friends, fans, agents, publishers, and others. Among some of the notable correspondents are Lord Edgar Douglas Adrian, Sir Leopold Amery, Maurice Baring, Lord Ronald Gorell Barnes, Lord Max Beaverbrook, John Betjeman, Laurence Binyon, Sir Nevile Bland, Gordon Bottomley, Sir Angus Cunninghame Graham, Lord George Derwent, Morris L. Ernst, E. M. Forster, Sir Ralph Furse, Sir Stephen Gaselee, Oliver St. John Gogarty, Cosmo Gordon Lang (Archbishop of Canterbury), Loelia Mary Grosvenor Lindsay (Duchess of Windsor), Alfred R. McIntyre, Margaret Haig Thomas Mackworth (Viscountess Rhondda), Sir Edward Marsh, Charles J. B. Masefield, John Masefield, Sir Charles Mendl, Naomi Mitchison, Sir Owen St. Clair O'Malley, A. D. Peters, Raymond Queneau, I. A. Richards, Denys Kilham Roberts, V. Sackville-West, Elisabeth Schumann, Lord William Strang, Edward Weeks, Dame Rebecca West, and Steuart Wilson. An index of all correspondents appears at the end of this inventory.
Acquisition:
Gift, 1975
Access:
Open for research
Ann Bridge Papers--Folder List
- Manuscripts of Books, 1932-1969 (Contents Page Item (1); Author's Inventory p. 1-19)
  - Peking Picnic (1932) (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - The Ginger Griffin (1934) (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - The Ginger Griffin (continued) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Illyrian Spring (1935) (Box 3, Folder 3-7)
  - Illyrian Spring (continued) (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Enchanter's Nightshade (1937) (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Enchanter's Nightshade (continued) (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
  - Enchanter's Nightshade (continued) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Four-Part Setting (1939) (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
  - Four-Part Setting (continued) (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Singing Waters (1946) (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - The House at Kilmartin (1951) (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - The House at Kilmartin (continued) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Dark Moment (1952) (Box 9, Folder 2-6)
  - The Dark Moment (continued) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - A Place to Stand (1953) (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
  - Portrait of My Mother (1955) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Portrait of My Mother (continued) (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - The Light-Hearted Quest (1956) (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - The Light-Hearted Quest (continued) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Portuguese Escape (1958) (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
  - The Portuguese Escape (continued) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Numbered Account (1960) (Box 13, Folder 2-5)
  - The Tightening String (1962) (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - The Dangerous Islands (1964) (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
  - The Dangerous Islands (continued) (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Emergency in the Pyrenees (1965) (Box 15, Folder 3-6)
  - Emergency in the Pyrenees (continued) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Episode at Toledo (1966) (Box 16, Folder 2-5)
  - Facts and Fictions (1968) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Facts and Fictions (continued) (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - The Malady in Madeira (1969) (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
  - The Malady in Madeira (continued) (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
- Appendices, A-R (Contents Page Item (1) (continued); Author's Inventory, p. 20-99)
  - Appendix A (transcripts of Masefield letters, 1911- 12, p. 20; see also folders 29.5-29.6) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Appendix B (Verses, 1905-62, p. 21) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Appendix C (Short stories, 1911-60, p. 23) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Appendix D (Unpublished, p. 25)
    - Illusion (1922) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - George Mallory (1924) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - The Frolic in Western Waters (1925) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - The Bright Idea (1928) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Level Now With Men (1939) (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
  - Appendix E (File G M, 1963, p. 26) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Appendix F (China letters, 1925-27, p. 27; see also folder 28.7) (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Appendix F (continued) (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Appendix G (Articles and descriptive pieces, 1927- 63, p. 32) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Appendix H (File Z various letters, 1923-50, p. 35) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Appendix I (7 letters about trip to Dalmatia, 1930, p. 44) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Appendix J (Lectures, 1932-44, p. 46) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Appendix K (3 letters about trip to Albania, 1935-36, p. 47) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Appendix L (9 letters from Portugal, 1946-47, p. 48) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Appendix M (Enquiries about Portrait of My Mother, ca. 1815-1954, p. 50; see also folder 28.8)
    - File A (ca. 1953-54, p. 50) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - File B (ca. 1953-54, p. 52) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - File C (ca. 1815-1954, p. 53) (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - File D (ca. 1953, p. 57) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Appendix N (File Y general letters, 1924-56, p. 59) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Appendix O (War-time letters, 1937-44, p. 79) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Appendix P (Reviews by AB, 1944-53, p. 81) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Appendix Q (File W letters, complications for a novelist who is also the wife of a diplomat, 1932-47, p. 82; see also folder 29.7) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Appendix R (File X diplomatic episodes, 1926-48, p. 91; see also folders 29.2, 29.7) (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Contents Page Item (1) (continued); Author's Inventory, p. 100
  - Children's verses, nd (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Letters from AB to Eva O'Malley, 1926-57 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Photograph album (Dalmatia), ca. 1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Climbers' Club Journal, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Contents Page Items (2) - (14)
  - (2) Albums containing newspaper clippings and/or letters
    - Vol. I ( Peking Picnic, 1932-33, including correspondence 1931-45) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Vol. II ( The Ginger Griffin, Illyrian Spring, The Song in the House, Enchanter's Nightshade, 1934-37, including correspondence 1937-56) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Vol. III ( Enchanter's Nightshade, Four-Part Setting, Frontier Passage, Singing Waters, 1937-46, including correspondence 1937-38) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Vol. IV ( And Then You Came, The Dark Moment, A Place to Stand, 1948-53, including correspondence 1948-54) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Vol. V ( Portrait of My Mother, The Light- Hearted Quest, The Selective Traveller in Portugal, 1949-57, including correspondence 1949-56) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Vol. Va ( The Selective Traveller in Portugal, 1946-47) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - (3) Contents of box file labelled George Mallory (1963, nd) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - (3) Contents of box file labelled George Mallory (continued) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - (4) Manuscript of Permission to Resign (1971) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - (5) Manuscript of Julia in Ireland (1973) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - (5) Manuscript of Julia in Ireland (continued) (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - (6) U.S. reviews of The Numbered Account, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - (7) Letters from the U.S.A., 1941-42 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - (8) Folders of material relating to:
    - Dangerous Islands, 1961-62 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Singing Waters, 1944-46 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Peking Picnic and other novels set in China [duplicate transcripts of items in Appendix F, see also folders 19.9- 20.2] (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Portrait of My Mother [duplicate transcripts of items in Appendix M, see also folders 21.5-22.1] (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - The Tightening String, 1960-61 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - (9) Material relating to the International Refugee Organisation, Rome, 1947-1948 [some duplicates of File X; see also folder 22.6] (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - (10) Lectures and lecture notes, 1937, nd (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - (11) Verses and folk-songs collected by AB, nd (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - (12) Originals of letters, 1911-12, 1939 [originals of Appendix A; see also folder 18.4] (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - (13) Copies of some letters, 1911-12 [transcripts of Appendix A; see also folder 18.4] (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - (14) Diplomatic episodes, 1941-45 [transcripts of Files W X; see also folders 22.5-22.6] (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Materials found, but not described on Contents Page or in Author's Inventory
  - Manuscript of Moments of Knowing (1970) (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
  - Manuscripts of miscellaneous short pieces, ca. 1933-65, nd (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
  - Manuscripts of miscellaneous short pieces (continued) (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs, ca. 1907-1940s, nd (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
Index of Correspondents
Acker, Charles E. ( Baldwin-Lima-Hamilton Corp.)--21.6
Ader, Richard M.; (Greenbaum, Wolff Ernst)--21.5, 21.6
Adrian, Edgar Douglas Adrian, Baron, 1889-1977--21.5
Aglen, John, Sir--22.6
Airey, T. S.--22.1
Amery, L. S. (Leopold Stennett), 1873-1955--20.4
Argun, Mübeccel ( BBC Turkish Section)--25.2
Argyll, Duke of--29.1, 29.11
Armstrong, Ronald--20.4
Arnold-Foster, Ka--20.4
Austen-Leigh, Emma--22.2
Baddeley, Vincent, Sir--21.5, 21.7
Baldwin, John M.--21.7
Baranyai, Leopold, Mrs.--25.1
Baring, Maurice, 1874-1945--22.2
Barnes, Ronald Gorell Barnes, Baron, 1884-1963--20.4
Barr, J. R. S. ( British Embassy, Ankara)--20.4
Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, 1879-1964--22.6
Bell, May--22.2
Berry, W. A. (Miss) ( Engineering)--21.6
Bessenyey, G., Baroness--25.2
Betjeman, John, Sir, 1906 6- --21.5
Bilew, Elizabeth--24.1
Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943 ( British Museum)--20.4
Bishop, T. ( Iron Coal Trades Review)--21.6
Blakelock, Denys--25.2
Bland, Nevile, Sir, b. 1886--22.6
Blauvelt, James H. (Mrs.)--26.1
Bontells, Katharine--24.1
Bottomley, Gordon, 1874-1948--20.4
Bridges, Monica--20.4
Bryant, R. W. G.--25.2
Bunnell, Frank S.--21.7, 22.1
Burrell, Doris--26.1
Calderón, Doña Joséfina Attard de--22.5
Callender, J. Graham ( National Museum of Antiquities of Scotland)--20.4
Campbell, George, Sir--21.5, 25.2, 29.1
Campbell, Olive--21.5
Carey, Joyce--20.4
Carr, Lily--20.4
Cazenove, C. F. ( Literary Agency of London)--18.4, 29.5
Cheke, Marcus, Sir--26.1
Childe, V. Gordon (Vere Gordon), 1892-1957--22.2
Clark, Alexander Frederick Bruce, 1884- --20.4
Coleman, H. T. ( Canadian Pacific Railway Company)--21.6
Collingwood, Robin G.--20.4
Collins, Arthur J., Jr. ( Collins Nurseries)--20.4
Cooper, W. V. (Wilbraham Villiers), 1876- --22.6
Couto, Joao, 1892- ( Art Museum of Lisbon)--26.1
Crowe, Lady--20.4
Cunninghame Graham, Angus, Sir, 1893-1981--22.2, 25.2
Daniels, [Catharina] Polak--20.4
Darvall, Frank ( Ministry of Information)--28.4
Davidson, Basil, 1914- --22.4
Davis, Guy R.--24.1
Dawson, William--21.6
Day, Emory C.--21.7, 22.1
Day, James Ingersoll--21.7, 22.1
Day, Jane--28.8
Day, Marie Louise--see Sanders, Marie Louise Day
Day, May--21.7, 22.1
Day, Robert Borland--21.7, 22.1
Day, William--21.7
Dearmer, Percy, 1867-1936--24.1
Derwent, George Harcourt Johnston, Baron, 1899-1949--22.6
Desborough, Ethel, Lady--22.2
Dodgson, Campbell, 1867-1948 ( British Museum)--20.4
Doty, Robert C. ( Preparatory Commission for the International Refugee Organization)--22.6, 29.2
Dryburgh, D. J. W. ( Taylor and Humbert)--21.5
Edwards, L. Brooke--21.6
Elliott, Barbara--20.4
Ernst, Margaret--22.1
Ernst, Morris L. (Morris Leopold), 1888- ( Greenbaum, Wolff Ernst)--21.6, 22.1, 26.1
Finberg, H. P. R. ( University College, Leicester)--21.5
Finnie, W. M. ( Bedford Office, Tavistock)--21.5
Fisher, James--20.4
Forster, Arnold--20.4
Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan), 1879-1970--22.2
Fremantie, Sydney R.--25.2
French, J. F. ( Library of the Foreign Office)--28.6
Furse, Ralph Dolignon, Sir, 1887- --21.5, 22.2, 25.2
Gaselee, S. (Stephen), 1882-1943 ( Library of the Foreign Office)-- 20.3, 20.4, 22.2, 22.5
Gaston, D. A.--22.6
Geraldine of Albania--28.6
Gilbert, Rodney, b. 1889--22.6
Gilder, P. D.--22.6
Gill, Evan R.--26.1
Glazebrook, George E.--25.2
Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1878-1957--25.2
Gollars, Harry W.--24.1
Gosford, L. L. Louise, Dowager Countess of--22.2
Gould, Gerald, 1885-1936--24.1
Granville, Rose, Lady--20.4
Gravenslede, J. W. ( Stow Hill Bible Tract Depot)--21.5
Gray, A. Herbert--25.2
Gray, Hugh ( Preparatory Commission for the International Refugee Organization)--22.6, 29.2
Grigg, P. J.--24.1
Halsey, Decca Singleton--21.7, 22.1
Harris, Peter--21.5, 21.7
Hatchards Booksellers--20.4
Hatherly, C. G. ( Messrs. Sandberg)--21.6
Haupt, Edith--21.7, 22.1
Hayes, Richard J., 1902- ( National Library of Ireland)--21.7, 22.1
Headlam-Morley, K. ( Iron and Steel Institute)--21.6
Hedin, Alma Isabel Sofia, 1876- --22.6
Hedin, Sven Anders, 1865-1952--22.6
Hill, C. V.--21.7, 22.1
Hill, Carol--28.4
Hinman, Hannah--21.7
Hodson, Cora Sanders--22.3
Howell, Henry W. (Mrs.)--22.1
Hutchinson, F. E. (Francis Ernest), 1871-1947 ( All Soul's College)--20.4
Iddesleyh, Elizabeth--26.1
Ironmonger, The--21.6
Irwin, Elizabeth--20.4
Irwin, Margaret--20.4
James, David--20.4
Jenkins, S. G. ( Tavistock Urban District Council)--21.5
Jersey, M. E., Dowager Countess of--20.4
Jesse, F. Tennyson (Fryniwyd Tennyson), 1888-1958--24.1
John, Augustus--22.6
Johnson, Peer P.--22.2
Johnston, Reginald Fleming, Sir, 1874-1938--20.4
Johnstone, R. W. (Robert William), 1879- --25.2
Kemp, P. K.--22.1
Kennedy, Irene--20.4
Kennedy, Virginia [Lady Pye]--20.4
King, A. J. ( Boosey and Hawkes Ltd.)--21.5
King, Eliza Trumbull--21.7
Kokoschka, Oskar, 1886- --22.6
Lamb, Mabel--20.4
Lang, Cosmo Gordon Lang, baron, Abp. of Canterbury, 1864-1945--20.4, 25.1
Lewis, Cecil--24.1
Lewis, Elise Lathrop--21.7
Lindsay, Loelia Mary Grosvenor, Duchess of, 190 2- --24.1
Lochhead, John L. ( Marines Museum)--21.7, 22.1
Locomotive, The--21.6
Long, John C. ( Bethlehem Steel Co. Inc.)--21.6, 26.1
Macartney, Professor ( All Soul's College)--25.2
Macdonald, (Mrs.)--20.4
Macgillivray, Mary ( Office of the High Commissioner for Canada)--21.6
MacKenzie, Colm--21.5
Mackworth, Margaret Haig Thomas, Viscountess Rhondda, b. 1883 ( Time and Tide)--22.4, 25.2
Maclehose, James--20.4
Malcolm, Jeanne, Lady--20.4
Manson, J. B.--25.1
Marsh, Edward Howard, Sir, 1872-1953 ( Georgian Poetry)--24.1
Masefield, Charles J. B. (Charles John Beech), 1882-1917--18.4, 29.5, 29.6
Masefield, John, 1878-1967--18.4, 29.5, 29.6
Matson, Harold--22.1
Maxwell, John Stirling--25.2
McEvoy, H. M.--21.5
McIntyre, Alfred R. ( Little, Brown, and Co. Publishers)--24.1, 25.1, 28.6
McLysaght, Edward ( National Library of Ireland)--21.7
Mendl, Charles, Sir, 1871-1958--20.3
Metcalf, Isaac Stevens--21.7
Mitchison, Naomi, 1897- --25.2
Monkswell, Robert, Lord--21.5
Moody, Sarah S.--24.1
Mortensen, J.--24.1
Napier, Albert, Lord--21.5
Napier, Gladys, Lady--21.5
Nettleship, Ursula (Battle) --21.5
Newton, Basil--22.6
Noble, Lilias--22.2
Norris, Nora--21.7, 22.1
Notley, A. C. ( London Metal Exchange)--21.6
O'Malley, Diana Jane Sabina--20.4, 21.1, 22.6
O'Malley, Owen St. Clair, Sir, 1887-(Angus) --22.5, 22.6, 24.1, 29.7
Packard, W. V. ( The Iron Age)--21.6
Packman, James ( Royal Empire Society)--21.6
Palmella, Duchess of--26.1
Patterson, Virginia H. ( Macmillan Co.)--25.2
Peacock, Helen ( Oxford University Press)--21.7, 22.1
Peake, Catherine, Lady--22.3
Pear, Tom Hatherley, 1886- --22.2
Peel, Delia--20.4
Pendred, Benjamin Wildig ( The Engineer)--21.6
Peters, A. D.--20.4, 24.1, 24.2, 28.6
Peters, Martha Ann ( Howard Tilton Library)--21.7
Phillips, R. ( Council of the Isles of Scilly)--28.5
Pickering Inglis, Ltd.--21.5
Pierce, Tony ( Magdalene College)--21.6
Pirzio-Biroli, Giacomo--22.1
Preetorius, Leni--20.4
Prendergast, W. H. ( Engineering Dept., University College, Galway)--21.6
Prentice, C. H. C. ( Chatto and Windus Publishers)--24.1
Price, A. Whigham--24.2
Prince, O. I. ( National Library for the Blind)--24.1
Pye, David, Sir--22.2
Pye, Virginia, Lady--see Kennedy, Virginia
Queneau, Raymond, 1903-1976 ( Librairie Gallimard)--24.1
Rathbone, Ruby--26.1
Raymond, Harold, 1887- ( Chatto and Windus Publishers)--24.1, 28.6
Redward, Fred ( British Consolate)--25.2
Richards, I. A. (Ivor Armstrong), 1893- --22.2
Roberts, Denys Kilham, 1903-1976--22.3
Roberts, Walter--22.6
Robertson ( Office of the High Commission for Canada)--21.6
Robertson, David--19.8
Root, Donna L. ( Inland Seas)--21.7
Rose, Archie--22.2
Ross, Jean Lindsay--28.6
Rothschild, Marie de--20.4
Routt, Garland C. ( Foreign Service of the USA)--21.7, 22.1
Rowe, Dorothy--21.7, 22.1
Rutherford, W. P.--21.6
Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962--20.4
Safford, Edith M.--22.2
Sanders, Helen ("Chintz")--21.5 21.7, 22.1, 22.3
Sanders, Marie Louise Day--21.7, 28.8
Sanders, Tristie--21.5, 21.7, 22.1
Sauer, A. ( Michigan State Prison)--20.4
Saville, J. P. ( Iron and Steel Institute)--21.6
Schane, Marie--25.2
Schumann, Elisabeth--24.2
Schuster, Claude, Lord--22.2
Sedgewick, Ellery ( Atlantic Monthly)--20.4, 24.1
Sedgewick, Marjorie--20.4
Sharpe, Marjorie Bright ( Radio Station KITO)--20.4
Sheppard, Canon Dick--22.6
Silverman, Elizabeth--21.7, 22.1
Smallwood, Nora ( Chatto and Windus)--25.2
Smith, T. M. Dorrien--28.5
Snowden, Sara D.--21.7
Stephens, Ella--20.4
Stoddard, Marie--22.1
Strang, William Strang, Baron, 1893- --22.2, 22.6
Tablet, The--22.4
Taylor, Geoffrey, Sir--22.2
Teichman, Eric, Sir--20.4, 22.6
Teichman, Lady--22.6
Tennant, Ernest--21.5, 21.6
Thanson, J. B. ( Tate Gallery)--25.1
Tilley, John, Sir--22.6
Townsend, Ingersoll--21.7, 22.1
Tuam, Archbishop of--29.5
Tyler, Rosemary--30.3
Varrichione, Louis ( Preparatory Commission for the International Refugee Organization)--22.6, 29.2
Verney, Harry, Sir--24.2
Walck, Henry Z. ( Oxford University Press)--21.7
Waldesbuhl, T.--29.1
Walker, J. S. ( Walker, Fraser, Steele)--21.5
Warner, Roger S.--20.4
Watt, R. P. ( A. P. Watt and Sons)--24.1
Weeks, Edward, 1898- ( Atlantic Monthly Press)--20.4, 24.1
West, Rebecca, Dame, 1892- --22.2
White, A. S. ( War Office)--21.5
Williams, Harold--22.6
Wilson, Claude, 1860-1937--20.4
Wilson, J. G. ( Bumpus Ltd.)--20.4
Wilson, Steuart--20.4, 24.1
Young, Alfred--20.4